WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Cora.
Hello, Rosamund.
You made good time.
I say!
What?
Some man has opened a nudist colony
at Wickford in Essex,
called the Moonella Group.
What do you mean,
a man has opened a colony in Essex?
Not that sort of colony, Mama.
It's for people who want
to take all their clothes off.
In Essex? Isn't it terribly damp?
Would that make a difference?
Well, yes, if you had no clothes on.
Well, I think it's a mad idea.
Oh, I doubt
they were aiming it at you.
I wanted to come after Mary told me
about the farmer's child
you're taking such an interest in.
Come to my room when you're changed.
How long are you here for?
About a week, if I'm allowed.
Good. We're giving a bash
for my Deputy Lieutenants on Friday.
You can stay and help.
I'm afraid I'll be away
on Thursday night.
It's another of my Lord Loot things.
I'm guest of honour at a dinner for all
the Yorkshire-based commanding officers.
You're staying the night?
It's in Sheffield,
and it'll be very late,
so it seems sensible.
You'll just have to make do
with Cora.
And Edith and Tom and Rose.
What news of your suitor?
I haven't heard from him lately.
Have you decided what answer
you're going to give him yet?
Well, I think I should tell him
before I tell you. Wouldn't you agree?
Ellen Terry has nothing on you when
it comes to stringing out a moment.
Oh, are you busy?
No, no, no. Come in.
How can I help?
Would you like me to leave?
Oh, I'd love to think I had a secret
that was too indelicate
for a lady's ear, but I haven't.
No, I've got some good news,
for a change.
An old aunt's died.
No, that's not the good news,
but she made old bones.
Which is the main thing.
Well, the point is,
she's left me a bit of money.
Ah. It's a few hundred quid,
more than I've ever saved.
I am glad for you.
Well, she was married to a baker
and he did well, but they had no children.
How nice of her to choose you.
Well, I think it was in memory
of my dad, more than anything.
She and he were very close -
And you want my advice on what to do
with the inheritance? Is that it?
It is.
You'd do better asking Mr Branson's
advice. Or Dr Clarkson's.
She's asking mine.
But we live so out of the way here.
You need to talk to someone
who's still in the game.
I'll give it some thought,
Mrs Patmore.
And now, if you'll allow me,
I will go up and ring the gong.
Come and sit here and we can talk.
I'm not going to eat you.
But you are going to chew me up.
Why not just tell me about
the dear little farmer's daughter?
What did Mary say?
No more than that.
You knew I'd bring her back.
I feared it.
And I still feel very sorry
for poor Mrs Schroder.
I wrote to her. She told me
she's adopted another baby.
Then she has solved her problem,
but the question remains:
have you solved yours?
Am I at least going to be allowed
to see the girl?
Do you want to?
Of course.
I gave up ten months of my life to
make sure she came safely into the world.
The trouble is, the farmer's wife,
Mrs Drewe,
she just thinks I'm a nuisance.
She doesn't want me to see Marigold.
So, we have a situation of infinite
danger to your reputation,
which brings you no emotional reward
to compensate.
Are we the first down?
It looks like it. Want some?
Mmm.
How is Miss Bunting?
Still teaching Daisy downstairs?
She is. But don't worry.
I won't ask her to join us
in the future.
Cora would overrule me in a moment
if she thought it important to you.
Which you don't think it should be?
I know you feel excluded at times,
an outsider in your own home.
Look, I am very grateful to you
and this family.
But my vision of this country
is different from yours.
But not from Miss Bunting's?
I believe in reform
and the moral direction of the Left,
and when I'm with her,
I don't feel like a freak or a fool,
devoid of common sense.
I would only say this, Tom:
In your time here you've learned
both sides of the argument,
befriended people
you'd once have seen as enemies.
That's true.
You should be proud.
Five years ago, would you have believed
you could be friendly with my mother?
I'm not sure I'd have
believed it five minutes ago.
Don't make nothing
of what you've achieved. That's all.
Drinks before dinner?
Wait till Carson catches you.
You'll notice I poured them myself.
Anna, I've had a note
from Sergeant Willis.
He says he's going to look in
this morning at 11 o'clock.
To see me?
That's what he says.
Anyone else, Mr Carson?
I'm not sure.
He says he wants to talk
to Anna and Lady Mary.
Lady Mary? Why her?
I don't know.
But could you warn her?
I'll tell her
when I take up the breakfast tray.
May I ask... to what do I owe
the pleasure of this visit?
I'll get straight down to it.
You know how Lord Merton likes to...
display his interest
in all things medical?
At least, he likes to,
when in the company of Mrs Crawley.
Your confidence is a compliment.
I confide in you, Dr Clarkson,
because I must.
Only you can help.
That is more flattering still.
It's the family's fault, really.
We've trained her in our ways, and the
earnest and intellectual 'bonne bourgeoise'
has been replaced by...
a rather less definable figure.
Are you saying you liked her better
when she was more middle-class?
No, I wouldn't go that far.
But you understood her better.
Precisely.
Now I do not know who she is.
I do not know what it is she wants.
Well, there are many who wouldn't
be puzzled by the desire
to marry a lord
and live in a palace.
Can I ask you a personal question?
I've lived through great wars
and my share of grief.
I think I can manage an impertinent
question from a doctor.
Do you perhaps resent the idea of a
change of position for Mrs Crawley?
I'm sorry.
I do not quite grasp your question.
It bewilders me.
But I will say this:
Do you wish to see her live a life
devoid of industry and moral worth?
I do not.
And when the glitter is tarnished,
you know, what then?
A hollow existence
in a large and draughty house,
with a man who bores her to death.
It's a terrible prospect.
So our duty is clear.
Oh... It's you, m'lady.
Yes. I wanted to bring my aunt
to meet Marigold.
This is Lady Rosamund Painswick.
May I introduce Mrs Drewe?
How do you do, Mrs Drewe?
We're sorry for dropping in like
this. I expect you're very busy.
I am busy, m'lady, yes.
This is Marigold.
Oh, I do see. She's very sweet.
Lady Edith seems to think so.
Hello.
Lady Edith has decided to show off
the baby to her aunt.
Lady Rosamund Painswick.
Pleased to meet you, m'lady.
Well, we don't want
to disturb your day.
I've got to get the dinner started.
Yes, of course.
Goodbye, dear.
Remember your...
Remember your friend, Rosamund.
I should take her inside.
Oh, I could always -
I'll take her.
Of course.
Goodbye.
Well?
It's exactly
what I said would happen.
She wants Marigold as her toy,
to be poked and prodded by every
stray guest from the big house!
And you've done this.
You've done it!
What did you mean
by saying to Mrs Patmore
we were living our lives
out of the way, not in the game?
Well, we are.
Why does everyone talk as if
we don't live in the modern world?
You don't agree with that, then?
No.
Does the King not live in the world
of today?
Does Mr Sargent not paint
modern pictures?
Does Mr Kipling not write
modern books?
So, what are you going to tell her?
I don't know yet. I shall consider.
Sergeant Willis is asking for you,
Mr Carson.
He's got a man with him
from London, he says.
They're in the library now.
They?
An Inspector's come
from Scotland Yard.
What does he want with me?
What does he want with any of us?
None of it makes any sense.
By the way, I'd like to catch
the ten-o'clock train tomorrow.
I'm dining with Mr Blake
and I don't want to be in a rush.
Will we stay at Lady Rosamund's?
She doesn't mind. She's told Mead.
Will you see Lord Gillingham?
I don't think so.
So you haven't changed your mind?
Right. Let's get this over with.
Have I finished us off
before we ever really got started?
You've pitted yourself against them
from the start.
How can you retreat
from that position?
You mean I've made it 'them or me'?
Haven't you?
You despise the family, but I think
you forget my wife was one of them.
My child IS one of them.
Where does that leave me?
Don't you despise them? Really?
No, I don't.
I'd like things to change, but I don't think
in black-and-white terms any more.
While I do?
Look, I'm not going to pretend
I haven't enjoyed knowing you.
In fact, I'm relieved to know I'm
not the only Socialist left on this earth.
But maybe we should call it a day,
before one of us gets hurt.
I don't know what else to add,
Mr Vyner.
I remember we had to race
to catch the train.
I'd had lunch with Lord Gillingham
and I needed to get home,
as the church fete was planned
for the following day.
And it was during the fete
that Lord Gillingham arrived
with the news of Mr Green's death?
That's right. And I told Anna.
Hmm.
Was it a great surprise?
I think I would have
called it a shock.
She was very shocked.
Was she? Was she, indeed?
Can I go now? I think Lady Mary
has given what help she can.
Erm... will you confirm
that Mrs Bates was in London
on the morning that Mr Green died
and that you don't know where?
I only have to ask her.
Secondly,
you have no reason to believe
that Bates was anywhere
further south than York?
No reason at all.
I think they'd enjoy
getting to know each other better.
I think it's a nice idea,
but shouldn't I do it, for once?
I always seem to be taking luncheon
off you.
No, I'd rather.
You see, Mrs Potter likes
to have people to cook for.
And Spratt needs something
to occupy his mind.
Oh?
We both have an inkling that my maid
Collins is on the way out.
Oh, I do hope not.
No, I don't mean she's dying.
I mean she's on her way
out of my house.
She keeps talking
about her mother being infirm.
But I'm infirm.
Why doesn't she think about that?
You're as infirm as Windsor Castle.
And why does Spratt mind,
particularly?
Because he likes things
to be just so.
But also,
I think Collins was his creature
and does his bidding
without qualm or query.
He can't be sure of that
in the next one.
Well, never having had a lady's maid, it's
not a challenge I've had to tussle with.
But you'll come on Thursday?
I will.
I think it would be nice
for Doctor Clarkson
to see beyond Lord Merton's
position and get to know the man.
I agree.
Oh!
I knew I had something to tell you.
Shrimpie thinks he may be
on the trail of Princess Kuragin.
Oh, I am pleased.
Yes, he's heard a rumour of some
Russian nurses working in...
Wan... Wan Chai?
And that's in Hong Kong?
Well, nearby, I think.
Well, it sounds much better
than it might have been.
Yes. The idea of Princess Irina
scrubbing the sick
and emptying bedpans
is a cheering one.
Will you tell her husband? No,
I'll wait until Shrimpie is certain.
These things
must be managed carefully.
Yes.
Sounds as if this must be managed
very carefully.
Why did Mr Carson try to hide
that you were in London on that day?
I don't think he tried to hide
anything. He just forgot.
Isn't it a big thing when a member
of the staff goes to London?
Not for a lady's maid.
Mrs Hughes, please.
She's right. It's not a big thing
for ladies' maids or valets.
I'm going tomorrow with Lady Mary.
And you liked Mr Green?
Yes. I did. Very much.
He wasn't so fond of your husband.
Well,
there's no accounting for taste.
Don't go away, Mrs Bates.
You've said you'll be in London.
I've no objection.
But don't go away.
I'm very sorry, My Lord.
I wonder if you know when we can
get in here and lay the table.
The police have taken over the
library, and I needed to spread these out.
What are they for? I'm trying to
formulate my plans for the village,
and I'm looking into some builders.
You won't use
the ordinary maintenance team?
It would be beyond them.
Have you made your choice?
I'll have to talk to Lady Mary,
but I like the look of this outfit.
They're based in Thirsk, so they're
local, and their work is excellent.
Of course,
we should all invest in building.
Fortunes will be made
over the next few years.
Why don't I hold the bags,
while you do that?
Oh, that's frightfully nice of you!
Are you sure?
Quite sure.
Erm... I can have them back now.
I shouldn't dream of it.
Where are you going?
Erm... just to St Mary Magdalene's.
You must have a very sweet tooth!
No, they're not for me.
I give tea to some Russian refugees
every Tuesday and Thursday. They love cake.
I love cake.
Oh, come and have some, if you like.
Are you interested in Russia?
Not terribly...
although I am very sorry
for them all.
Of course.
I should be more interested, really.
Why?
I have a bit of Russian blood.
How extraordinary!
It's true.
In a way, my family is Russian.
Or, at least, they used to be.
Well, now I insist.
Come and have some tea.
By way of a thank-you.
I suppose we ought to introduce
ourselves, even if it feels funny.
Erm... Rose MacClare.
Atticus Aldridge, at your service.
That doesn't sound very Russian.
Well, we weren't called Aldridge
back then.
Mrs Patmore, I think I may have
a solution to your problem.
Oh, that's good to hear.
Why not invest
in the building trade?
With the expansion that's going on
everywhere, you'd soon see a good return.
Oh. Well, that's a thought.
Had you any special firm in mind?
What about WP Moss?
They're based in Thirsk, they're expanding,
and I hear their name everywhere.
I expect you keep your ear to
the ground about that sort of thing.
I like to keep abreast
of what's going on in the world.
So, can you buy shares in WP Moss?
I mean, have they gone public?
Well, erm...
you'll have to make enquiries.
Miss Bunting? I must confess
I am surprised to see you here.
Rest easy, Mr Carson.
I've come to say goodbye.
She's leaving the school, isn't she?
She's leaving the school
and the village, because Mr Branson
won't stand up to His Lordship.
You are nudging impertinence, Daisy.
I should think carefully
before you say one more word.
Are you going? Honestly?
I am, but the situation's
not quite as Daisy recounted it.
We already knew that.
I've had an offer, from a school
in Preston, in Lancashire.
A grammar school, no less,
so it's quite a step up.
I dithered a bit,
but I've decided to accept.
Because she gets insulted
when she comes here.
I am sure Miss Bunting is given
the reception she deserves.
Mrs Patmore...
Don't let Daisy give up her studies.
She's got potential.
What's going on here?
All sorts.
Mr Carson's giving me investment advice
and Miss Bunting's leaving Downton,
because Mr Branson
won't stick up for her.
Well, that seems to cover it.
I'll be in my room.
Well, goodbye... and good luck.
Goodbye.
Ah, Mrs Hughes.
Who is this Mr Vyner?
He's the London detective,
looking into the death of Mr Green.
Why do they keep questioning
Mr and Mrs Bates?
Who says they do?
This house has no secrets.
Then I suggest you ask Mr Vyner.
I may just do that.
Who knows?
I might have something to tell him.
Don't make trouble, Mr Barrow.
Are you saying
I shouldn't do my duty, Mrs Hughes?
No.
I'm asking you not to make trouble.
Are you quite well? You look
as if you could do with a lie down.
Don't worry about me.
Who was that on the telephone?
Simon Bricker.
Oh, God. What did he want?
I shall answer
without commenting on your tone.
He wants the picture photographed
for his book.
When is this? He comes tomorrow and
they take the pictures on Friday.
Well, you know I won't be here.
I've got the dinner in Sheffield.
Since you don't like him,
I don't see that as a drawback.
And Mary's in London.
What difference does that make?
It's not that I dislike him, exactly.
It's that this business
has been dragging on.
Robert, it's a compliment.
By referencing our painting in his book,
he'll increase its value,
maybe by a lot. Is that so bad?
You're not forbidden
from inviting him.
Good, because I already have.
Mr Branson, sir.
Hello, Daisy. What can I do for you?
You can do something for yourself. You're
making the biggest mistake of your life.
Is this Miss Bunting, by any chance?
She's an extraordinary person.
Clever and kind.
She's all of those things.
Then why turn your back on her?
Daisy -
I mean it.
She's leaving tomorrow,
but I know she loves you.
I can tell when she speaks of you.
She's leaving tomorrow? For good?
Won't you stop her?
You're not a Crawley.
You belong with us.
We're the future. They're the past.
Well, I can hear her voice in that.
Daisy?
What are you doing here?
She was checking something
in the dining room. I held her up.
Get back downstairs immediately.
Mr Carson.
Have any of you heard of someone
called Atticus Aldridge?
He sounds like the hero of a novel
by Mrs Humphrey Ward.
I'm not sure. Any more clues?
I met him today. In York.
Marsha George told me his father's
been made Lord Sinderby.
Now, wait a minute. I remember this.
When the title was created, the locals were
furious, but now I can't remember why.
Perhaps because Sinderby's a Yorkshire
village and they'd only just bought a house.
Canningford Grange.
Oh! Have the Wheelers sold up?
You knew that. I told you.
What does My Lord Sinderby do?
Oh, I think he's a banker.
I don't know, really,
but the son's nice.
Oh... nothing like that!
Barrow, are you quite well?
Carson,
have you been over-working him?
Not that I'm aware, Your Ladyship.
Mr Barrow, am I ill-treating you?
You are the soul of kindness,
Mr Carson. Thank you, Mr Barrow.
I'm looking forward to your party.
It's very daring of the Lord
Lieutenant to give a cocktail party.
Carson, what do you think?
Well, I agree with Carson.
It seems very fast to me.
Well, I love cocktail parties.
Me too.
You only have to stay 40 minutes,
instead of sitting for seven courses,
between a deaf landowner
and an even deafer Major General.
Even so, they'll say you're not
doing things 'properly' any more.
Do you care what people think?
Yes.
I accept change,
but I want to navigate it gently.
I don't want to leap into it
and put everyone's backs up.
But why do the rituals, the clothes
and the customs, matter so much?
Because, without them, we would be
like the Wild Men of Borneo.
I disagree. Manners and tradition
are all very well,
but once they start to control us,
they've outlived their usefulness.
Well, there are more important
things to worry about
than whether or not Carson
minds serving cocktails.
Why is Carson in the line of fire?
What's he done wrong?
I'm sorry. Excuse me, Mama.
I've rather a headache.
What was that about? Rosamund,
you spent the afternoon together.
Did Edith say
anything was bothering her?
Oh, she's just very tired.
She'll be fit as a flea tomorrow.
That's nice of you.
I'll just let Mr Carson know.
Oh, could you leave it,
for a moment?
He's given me his view,
about my money.
He says I should put it
into a building firm, WP Moss,
or, if not them, then into some
other building opportunity.
And you don't want to?
It's not that, exactly.
But I don't know about building,
and I don't like to put money
into something I don't understand.
Then why did you ask him?
Because he's a man, I suppose.
I'm not sure
that's a good enough reason.
Nor am I now.
But I don't want
to hurt his feelings.
I wish men worried about our feelings a
quarter as much as we worry about theirs.
You seem very thoughtful.
I'm on the brink of a decision.
I just hope it's the right one.
Well, I won't ask what it's about.
But remember, Tom - make the right
choice for you and not for us.
You know, you're much nicer
than a lot of people realise.
Not always. Good night.
Good night.
I don't know what you mean, Mama.
You question my motives
every time I come here.
It's as if I weren't welcome.
Just tell me: what were you and Edith
discussing in such a huddle?
Well, it is very hard -
Rosamund, you are addressing
your mother, not the committee
of the Women's Institute.
I'm afraid you've read somewhere
that rudeness in old age is amusing,
which is quite wrong, you know.
It's about the child, isn't it?
That is the secret you share.
We both know you are not leaving
my house until I learn the truth.
So, shall I have a bed made up for you
here, or are you going to tell me now?
Mr Drewe... I have to see her.
It was a mistake
to bring your aunt here.
Margie feels that you want the child
to be your plaything.
How can she say that?
The fact is, I was wrong.
She won't have you here,
not any more.
You must leave us alone.
If you don't stop coming, she'll make
me give up the farm and move away.
But what about Marigold?
What do you mean? We'd take her.
But you can't. I won't allow it.
What would you suggest?
We bring her up to the Abbey
and leave her in the library?
I'm very sorry, m'lady.
It's not what I planned.
But I see no way round it.
People always think how healthy we
must be, living out in the country,
but the water's not as good
as it might be.
You mean the iodine deficiency?
I do.
I suppose you must get
a lot of goitres.
Er... quite a lot, yes.
It's sad so few people know
that the treatment is just iodine.
Too many suffer
when the solution is simple.
You've studied this?
I've just read a lot.
I wish I had studied it.
Luncheon is served, m'lady.
Do cheer up, Spratt.
Spratt is downcast,
because it is as I feared.
Collins has handed in her notice.
You don't like change, Spratt?
I detest it, madam.
Well, we all hate change, Spratt,
but we have to learn to live with it.
I don't hate change.
I find it exciting.
Remember - those customs
and ceremonies that people think
are the soul of England
were almost all invented
by the Victorians.
Quite right.
The truth is, they're well suited,
whether we like it or not.
And I don't believe he's faking
his interest in medicine.
I'm afraid I agree with you.
You must be off soon.
I'm just going to put him
in his uniform, and then we'll go.
You never told me
what the Inspector wanted yesterday.
Mainly because I'm not sure.
He asked me if I liked Mr Green
and why he didn't like you.
And what did you say?
I said I don't know, because I don't.
I promise you this.
Nothing bad is ever going to happen
to you again.
I hope that's true.
We'll sit by the fire,
with all our children around us,
and I'll make certain
that you are safe.
I wonder.
We both want it so much, but do you
believe it'll really happen?
I do. With all my heart.
Actually, I'm not sure about having
children 'all around us'.
How many are you planning on,
Mr Bates?
You nearly missed me.
You never told me you were going.
Who did?
Daisy.
My champion.
The school must be sorry.
Maybe.
I think I was rather a nuisance,
but I hope they'll miss me a bit.
I hope you'll miss me a bit.
I'll miss you a lot.
I've loved you, you know.
I could have loved you more
if you'd let me.
I'm glad we met.
You've reminded me of who I am,
and I'm grateful.
And I won't lose touch with that
again.
But I wish we'd met
before you ever knew them.
We need to get started, if you're
to catch the four o'clock, miss.
Let me.
Did you have a nice journey?
Excellent.
Thank you very much.
Hello, Lord Grantham.
You look very splendid.
We're ships that pass in the night,
Mr Bricker.
I have to go to Sheffield,
but I'll see you tomorrow,
if you're still here when I get back.
Goodbye, Cora.
So, here we are again.
I'm beginning to find Downton
quite home-like.
Good. You're very welcome.
As long as you behave.
What are you doing here?
In search of more cake?
I wanted to see you again,
before I went up to London
to start my new job at the bank.
Do you think I should buy
a bowler hat?
Let me introduce you. Prince Kuragin,
Count Rostov, this is Mr Aldridge.
I'm Mr Kuragin here.
Have you heard from Aunt Violet yet?
Even if your father finds her,
what happens next? To any of us.
We are strangers in a strange land.
Talk to Mr Aldridge.
His family were Russian,
but they've started a new life
in England, and so can you.
Where did they come from?
Odessa.
His great-grandfather
came with some of them in 1859.
See? I do remember what I'm told.
And then the rest of the family
followed in - 1871.
How brilliant! That's right.
He is not Russian.
Nikolai. Nye nado.
No, he's not Russian now, but -
They were not Russian then!
I'm sorry about that.
Nikolai, podozhdi!
I don't understand.
Erm...
I think he said we're not Russian,
because we're... we're Jewish.
Well, how did he know?
There were two big pogroms to drive out
the Jews from Odessa, one in 1859...
And 1871?
But it's still odd.
I mean, you're English now,
but you're still Jewish.
What's the difference?
Would you let me give you dinner
when you're in London?
I might.
We'll have to see.
What a treat. I haven't been
to Simpson's for ages.
We'll go straight to the table.
I've asked a friend to join us,
and I want you to behave.
Why wouldn't I?
Goodness. I wasn't expecting you.
Ditto.
I, happily, was expecting you both.
What is your scheme? That we now hold hands
and take a house by the sea together?
Not quite.
But I have an idea that may be,
as The Times advertisements say,
'to your mutual advantage'.
You've got to stop this.
You're poisoning yourself.
Just lay off.
Look at you. Sweating like a beast.
Just because Her Ladyship let you stay,
you think you can boss us all around.
Forgot the cream.
Oh, Miss Baxter, you may not think
I have the right to ask,
but now that Her Ladyship knows
the truth, might you tell me?
If you really want me to.
Mr Molesley! Now.
Yes, Mr Carson. Right away.
I don't think
I can be hearing this correctly.
No?
No.
You seem to suggest I should take the
discarded leavings of Lady Mary Crawley,
dust off the fluff
and put them on my own plate.
That's not what Charles meant.
Isn't it?
Good. What a relief.
Now we won't have to quarrel.
Mabel, you're in love with Tony
Gillingham. You know you are.
All I know is that Tony
broke off our engagement,
which I had not deserved,
because Mary
crooked her little finger at him.
It was his choice, not mine.
So you say.
But now you're bored.
You want someone else to play with.
So, to dry his tears and keep him
occupied, you toss him back to me.
This isn't my idea.
Well, it certainly isn't mine.
You know, you're cutting off
your nose to spite your face.
I'm going. Well, what shall we do
with your food?
Eat it, and I hope it chokes you.
That was a big success
What's your next suggestion?
No, I don't think we need another plan.
This was just a scene we had to play.
Can you put the fricassee there?
We'll share it.
Now, I'd like my beef pink,
but not raw.
You didn't linger very long
over your Port.
Because we'd both rather be
with the ladies.
Edith, dear. There's something
I'd like to show you in the library.
What's that, Granny?
Oh, it's just a particular book
you might find interesting.
How is your fiery friend,
Miss Bunting?
I notice we don't see her here
as much as we used to.
Do you wonder at it? Well,
it's good to be disagreed with.
Keeps you on your toes.
Then Lord Grantham must have been
on points from the moment
she walked through the door.
I hope you haven't broken with her.
She's gone. She left today.
Oh, I am sorry.
What about you, Rose? What happened
to the young man you met?
He's gone too.
He's starting a new job in London.
Oh, dear. What a sad conversation.
He was interesting.
He wasn't just the same old chap
one's supposed to dance with.
His family was unusual.
In what way? They came here
from Odessa. 60 years ago.
They were driven out by the pogroms,
but they've done well.
Well, yes, that is interesting.
I didn't tell you because I knew
you'd think it was a mistake.
I suppose it never occurred to you
that I might be right?
What do you expect me to do?
Send her back?
It's too late. We can't get
the child back to Switzerland,
and there's no point
in keeping her here.
What do you mean?
That woman, Mrs...
Drewe. Mrs Drewe. Well,
she's at the point of explosion.
We must get the child away.
But where would we go?
Not 'we', my dear.
There are schools that will take
children from any age.
We'll find one in France where
she'll be properly looked after.
I dare say you can even visit,
as long as you never reveal who you are.
It'll be... quite manageable.
And you agree with this, Granny?
Well, I know it sounds very harsh.
But what else are we to do?
We're going up.
Mama, the car's ready
whenever you want it.
Oh, thank you, Cora.
Good night.
We'll settle the details later.
But I promise you -
this is for the best.
Well, in my eyes,
that makes you innocent.
It makes you a victim of the crime,
quite as much as Mrs Benton.
Why didn't you tell me this before?
Because I knew you'd say it proved my
innocence, when it does no such thing.
I'd rather not hide from the truth,
thank you.
Don't hide, then. But don't punish
yourself for ever, either.
No. But I have learned.
And I won't ever be controlled again.
I must go.
Mr Barrow said you wanted me.
Oh, come in and sit down.
Mrs Patmore's got something to say.
What's that?
Oh, just how grateful I am
for your excellent advice.
Oh, you've taken it, then?
I have. In a way.
You've invested in building?
Well, she's invested in a building,
yes.
I've found a cottage
in Haughton-le-Skerne,
and I'm going to see it on Tuesday.
It's £300, so it's a big decision,
but you've given me the courage.
Oh, that's not what I meant at all.
I thought you wanted to be in the
market, to increase your capital.
Well, I'll rent it now and later
I thought I'd take in some lodgers.
It's got three bedrooms.
Oh, this is very small beer.
Mr Carson, it's my kind of beer,
and I know how to drink it.
But you gave her the idea,
didn't you? She's very grateful.
Oh, I am. It's good to hear advice
from a man of the world.
Well, I like to do what I can.
We feel thoroughly protected.
Have you forgotten something?
It's not your maid.
I waited till she'd gone.
You must leave.
Mr Bricker, you must leave.
I hope I didn't wake you.
No, not at all, m'lord.
Miss Baxter's only just come down,
so Her Ladyship will still be awake.
Mr Bricker, I've asked you twice
now. Will you please go?
You said yourself -
who knows when I'll be back?
Mr Bricker -
Don't pretend, Cora.
You know something's happened between us.
You know things have changed now.
I feel it and I know you do.
When did someone last cherish you?
When did someone even listen to you?
I've seen you with your family,
ignored and passed over.
None of this is any -
I'm glad you're still awake...
The dinner was over early.
It seemed easier to come back.
I'm sorry if it's a disappointment.
It isn't.
Mr Bricker was just leaving.
I'm not here at Lady Grantham's
invitation.
Then will you please leave at mine?
Robert, let him go.
You can't be surprised.
When you chose
to ignore a woman like Cora,
you must have known not every man
would be as blind as you.
Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop!
Mama?
Mama? Papa?
Is everything all right in there?
I'm so sorry, darling. Your father and I
were just playing a stupid game
and we knocked over a lamp.
Oh. If you're sure.
I'm sure, poppet.
Good night. Sleep tight.
I think that is my exit too.
Wait.
Golly. What a night.
I'll sleep in my dressing room.
Eat a proper breakfast and lunch. There won't
be time for more than a cup of tea later.
I'll try to make it up.
When you've finished your duties,
I'd appreciate any help you can give.
We'll clear the hall now.
But why aren't we giving
a proper dinner here?
I quite agree, Mrs Patmore.
Mrs Hughes would say
we must move with the times.
Yes. I would.
Do you have a bandage I can have?
Have you hurt yourself?
I haven't, no.
Mrs Bates, have you heard any more
from that policeman?
No.
Here we go. That's Lady Mary.
Do you think you will?
No. I hope not, anyway.
Why do you pester her with this?
Because I feel like it.
Mr Barrow. Upstairs, please.
You too, Mr Molesley.
The car is waiting, sir.
Your case is inside it.
Thank you, Carson.
Thank you.
The Lady Beaumont.
The Lord Howard of Glossop.
Lovely to see you.
Good evening.
Howard.
Lord Grantham.
I'd forgotten his father had died.
Thank you, Barrow.
Oh, thank you.
My dear,
we can't leave things as they are.
It's a tinderbox.
It could go up at any moment.
Granny, if I was to take her
to London -
Oh, don't be ridiculous, my darling.
Think.
All I'm saying is,
there must be another way.
Well, how can there be?
Mrs Reginald Crawley
and the Lord Merton.
Hello, Isobel.
It's cousin Isobel.
And her follower.
The Earl and Countess of Woolton.
I'm fine. May I sit down?
Are you tired?
No, but I rather foolishly twisted
my ankle getting out of the car.
Oh, dear. Be careful - Lord Merton
will have you on the operating table
before you can say 'knife'.
What about Lady Ingleby's pearls?
I was so jealous, I wanted
to snatch them off her throat!
Sir Henry and Lady Lawson.
Well, that's that.
And you're back at your books,
I see.
I'm not giving up -
don't think I will.
And I wouldn't want you to.
Right, I'm going up.
Don't forget the light.
Oh, gracious! Good evening, m'lady.
I didn't expect to see you down here.
Mr Carson said you'd all gone to bed.
I wanted to make a telephone call
without...
I wanted to make a private call.
And you thought
you'd use Mr Carson's phone?
I don't think he'd mind. Do you?
I'm sure he wouldn't.
Well, I'll leave you to it.
Good night, m'lady.
Good night.
I'd like to make a trunk call
to London.
The York & Ainsty are holding
a point-to-point at Canningford Grange.
Can you see Aunt Mary?
You were always asking if I need help.
Well, now's your chance. Help me.
If I talk to anyone, it'll be you.
Then talk to me. Please.
You're losing your sense
of the appropriate.
You're losing your sense of occasion.
You think I'm a murderer.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.